The other day I told you about the instrument that we have already within ourselves, for
前幾天我跟你提到在我們內里與生俱來的一個工具，可用於..
us to have our own Self-knowledge, which is an actualisation, which is an experience,
能幫助我們獲得自覺，是一種實現，一種親身體驗，
which is a happening by which we become That.
是一個發生的過程，一種我們「成為」的事件。
It is the becoming, it is not any brain washing or sermoning but it’s a becoming I’m talking
這是成為的過程，不是什麼洗腦或說教，而是我正在談論的「成為」。
about.
然後。
When we say, we are the seekers of Truth, how truthful are we about this seeking?
當我們自稱是真理的追尋者時，我們對於這樣的追尋究竟有多誠實？
This is one point we should try to understand.
這是我們應該試著理解的一點。
Are we really, genuinely seeking?
我們是否真的、誠心誠意在追尋？
Are we genuine about it, or we are doing it because it’s nice to say that we are seeking
我們是真心實意，還是只因為這麼說聽起來很好-
the Truth?
追尋真理?
If you have to seek something genuine, you have to be truthful yourself.
如果你想要真誠地追尋，自身必先誠實以對。
This is one of the greatest hurdles in Sahaja Yoga.
這是霎哈嘉瑜伽中最艱難的關卡之一。
Sahaja Yoga is a system by which you jump into the Truth itself.
霎哈嘉瑜伽是一種讓你直接躍入真理本身的修習體系。
You become the Truth, you don’t see the Truth, you don’t understand the Truth, but
你成為真理本身，你不僅看見真理或理解真理，而是
you become the Truth.
你成為真理。
It is most amazing thing that human beings don’t understand what to expect out of Truth.
最令人驚嘆的是，人類根本不明白對真理應該有甚麼期許。
They are seeking Truth but they have no conception about the absolute value of Truth.
他們追求真理，卻對真理的絕對價值毫無概念。
Truth, we cannot compromise.
真相，我們不能妥協。
It doesn’t have two sides: like you have day and night, you have right and wrong.
它沒有兩面性：不像有白天和黑夜，沒有對錯。
It’s absolute!
它是絕對的！
There is no compromise about it.
沒有妥協的餘地。
For example, as the other day I told you that when you get your realisation, you start feeling
舉例來說，前幾天我曾告訴你們，當你們獲得自覺時，會開始感受到
the cool vibrations flowing from your hand.
清涼的生命能量從手中淌出。
And these cool vibrations are the indication that the Divine power has started flowing
而這些清涼的生命能量流動，正是神聖力量開始運作的徵兆
through you.
透過你。
Now, these vibrations that you have are flowing through you like a cool breeze, are absolutely
此刻流經你全身如涼風般的這些生命能量，是絕對
genuine, they are much more genuine than genuineness, because human beings always have relative
真實的，它們比真實更為真實，因為人類總是以相對的
idea of genuineness.
概念來理解真實。
For example, say, if you take carbon atom- it can be placed in any way, it has got four
舉例來說，以碳原子為例，它可以任意排列，因為它具有四個
valencies, but it can be placed any way in a molecule.
化合價，但在分子中可以任意排列。
You can change the form of it, but still, if you go to the details of it, the carbon
你可以改變它的形式，但如果你深入探究，碳
will remain carbon.
依然還是碳。
And a hydrogen will remain hydrogen, in its basic structure.
氫原子始終會保持其基本結構，依然是氫原子。
So, the Truth that is the basic thing, cannot change.
所以，真理的根本是無法改變的。
You cannot mould it, you cannot befool it, you cannot act it.
你無法塑造它，無法愚弄它，也無法操控它。
When these vibrations are flowing from you, if there are no vibrations then you are not
當這些生命能量從你身上流動時，如果沒有生命能量，那就表示你還未
there.
成為真理。
Nobody can say that you are there, that you are a realised soul because you are carrying
沒有人能說你已成為，說你是一個自覺靈，只因為你頭上
a big horn on your head.
頂著一個大號角。
You may carry any signs and signatures saying that you are a great person, you have so many
你可以帶著任何標誌和印記，聲稱自己是個偉大的人物，擁有那麼多
following and there are so many people running mad after you.
跟隨者眾多，還有許多人瘋狂地追逐著你。
But still you are not a realised soul and you are not.
你依然不是個自覺靈，不是真理。
Even if you are crucified and you are a realised soul you can feel it that this one, the one
即使你被釘上十字架，即使你是個自覺靈，你也能感受到這一點，這個人，就是那個
whom we have crucified, is the one who is emitting vibrations.
我們釘上十字架的人，正是散發著生命能量之人。
But if the seeker is not truthful or is conditioned and he’s trying to cheat himself all the
但若求道者不誠實，或受到制約而總是自欺欺人
time, he is not going to gain anything.
那麼他將一無所獲。
In Sahaja Yoga you have to gain.
在霎哈嘉瑜伽中，你必須有所獲得。
Nobody else has to gain, it is you who has to gain.
無需他人獲益——必須獲得成長的，正是你自己。
So, you have to be genuine about it.
所以你必須真心誠意。
You cannot purchase it with money.
金錢無法買到它。
You cannot hide it by any false means.
任何虛假手段都無法掩蓋它。
You cannot kill it.
你也無法扼殺它。
It is eternal.
這是永恆的。
If you lose your vibrations in your hands- many people have told Me that “Mother, we’ve
如果你失去了手上的生命能量——許多人曾告訴我：「母親，我們已經
lost the vibrations, now, what to do?”
失去了生命能量，現在該怎麼辦？」
As if they have achieved something great by losing the vibrations, sometimes I feel.
有時候我覺得，他們似乎覺得失去生命能量是個偉大成就。
It’s a mistake!
這絕對是錯誤的觀念！
There’s something wrong with you somewhere which you must get it corrected.
你身上某處出了問題，必須改正才行。
If you think by talking or by befooling, by hiding things you are going to achieve anything,
如果你以為靠耍嘴皮子、裝瘋賣傻或隱瞞事實就能達成目的，
you are sadly mistaken.
那你就大錯特錯了。
So, we have to be extremely truthful to ourselves, we have not to cheat ourselves when we are
因此，我們必須對自己極度誠實，當我們面對
facing God, when we are facing Truth.
上帝、面對真理時，絕不能欺騙自己。
There are some people in this world who destroy others and there are some who destroy themselves.
這世上有會人摧毀他人，也有人會摧毀自己。
In the same way, there are some people in this world who cheat others and there are
同樣地，這世上有種人欺騙他人，也有種人
some who cheat themselves.
一些自欺欺人者。
There are so many things in this world which helps you to do that – is to cheat yourself.
這世上有太多事物幫你這麼做－就是欺騙自己。
So, be on the alert!
所以要提高警覺！
Like you read some books- they pamper your vanity, sometimes, pamper your ego and make
就像你讀某些書籍－它們有時會縱容你的虛榮心，助長你的自我膨脹
you feel ‘Oh, I’m all right, I feel all right!’
你會覺得『噢，我很好，我感覺很好！』
And you think that you have really achieved the goal that you wanted to, because certain
然後你以為你真的達成了你想要的目標，因為某些
books say ‘so, so, so, so…’
書上寫著『如此、如此、如此…』
Or maybe, somebody is a man who is not interested in your well-being and your Truth-seeking,
或者也許，有個人對你的福祉和追求真理並不感興趣，
may give you an idea that ‘All right, this is the Truth, all right!’
可能會讓你覺得「好吧，這是真理，沒錯！」
So, you believe that this is the Truth and you accept it, that this is the Truth.
於是，你相信這就是真理並且接受了它，認為這就是真理。
And with that kind of a conditioning, with that kind of an idea within your head, you
帶著這種制約，腦袋裡裝著這種想法，你
go ahead and carry on your life.
就這樣繼續過你的生活。
One life, two lives, three lives…
一輩子、兩輩子、三輩子……
You are supposed to be a seeker of Truth!
你本該是真理的追尋者！
How many lives are you going to waste seeking?
你還要浪費多少輩子去追尋？
Are you really genuine about it?
你對此真的誠心誠意嗎？
Or is it, because there is a fashion that one has to talk like that or similar/ly?
還是說，因為現在流行這樣說話或類似的表達方式？
Of course, to cheat other is, of course, is a sin, no doubt.
當然，欺騙他人無疑是一種罪過，這點毫無疑問。
But to cheat yourself, itself, is also a big obstacle in the seeking of Truth.
但欺騙自己本身，也是追尋真理的一大阻礙。
So, we have to realise that we are here to face the Truth.
所以，我們必須認知到，我們出世在這裡是為了面對真理。
And God has created us in such a way that He has placed everything so beautifully within
上帝以如此奇妙的方式創造了我們，祂將一切如此完美地安置在
us for this thing to happen, for us to get our Self-knowledge.
我們之內，為的就是讓我們獲得自覺。
You are not to go in wilderness to find it out!
你不需要遁入荒野去尋找它！
You are not to read anything about it!
你不需要閱讀任何相關的書籍！
Which university did Christ go to, or Krishna go to?
基督或克里斯納上過哪所大學？
What education did Rama have as far as university education is concerned?
就大學教育而言，羅摩受過什麼教育？
You have to read within yourself, your own book is within yourself, and to see for yourself,
你必須向內探尋，你(真我)的書就在你內裡，自己去讀，
in a very humble manner to understand, ‘Where am I?’
以非常謙卑的態度去理解：「我處在何處？」
Sahaja Yoga is a system which says, ‘saha-ja’- ‘saha’ means ‘with’ and ‘ja’ is
霎哈嘉瑜伽是一個體系，「霎哈嘉」（Saha-ja）－「霎哈」（Saha）意為「與…同在」，「嘉」（ja）
‘born’.
意為「誕生」。
It is born with you.
它是與生俱來的。
Everything born with you is genuine.
所有與生俱來的一切都是真實的。
Do you know that?
你知道嗎？
We do not know.
我們並不知道。
Our hands are genuine- they never cheat us.
我們的手是真實的——它們從不欺騙我們。
Our feet are genuine- they never cheat, do they?
我們的腳是真實的——它們從不欺騙，對吧？
Our eyes are genuine: you see something white, it looks white, it is white.
我們的眼睛是真實的：你看到白色的東西，它就是白色，那就是白色。
Our eyes never tell us that it is black.
我們的眼睛絕不會告訴我們那就是黑色。
Only when we are sick, then the whole composition changes and you get all kinds of wrong information
唯有當我們生病時，整個狀態改變了，你才會從你的身體
from this body of yours.
接收到各種錯誤的資訊
Your heart is genuine, but we teach our heart to cheat, we teach our eyes to cheat.
你的心是真實的，但我們卻教導自己的心去欺騙，教導眼睛去欺騙。
We have pretensions and the Truth knows you.
我們戴著虛假的面具，而真理深知你的本質。
When I say this we should not have self-pity about ourselves.
當我這麼說時，我們不該對自己產生自憐的情緒。
It is never the way to go from one extreme to another.
從一個極端走到另一個極端從來都不是解決之道。
This is a very common condition of human being.
這是人類非常普遍的現象。
If you tell them one thing, they go from one end to another end.
你跟他們講一件事，他們就會從一個極端走向另一個極端。
No, you just stand in the centre and see for yourself: How much genuine are we to receive
不，你只需站在中心點，自己觀察：我們有多真誠來領受
the blessings of God?
神的祝福？
Are we really seeking God or we are seeking something else behind the name of God?
我們真的是在尋求神，還是打著神的名號在追求其他東西？
I tell you, everyone who professes any religion should just have this test and he’ll be
我告訴你，每個自稱信仰任何宗教的人都該做這個測驗，結果會讓他
surprised that either he is seeking money out of Him or he is seeking power out of Him
大吃一驚——要麼他是在向神求財，要麼是在向神索權
or he is seeking some sort of a physical or maybe a material advantage of Him.
或者他是在追求某種身體或物質上的利益。
That is how we are disillusioned by these people who teach us about Truth, because we
這就是我們如何被這些所謂教導我們真理的人所蒙蔽，因為我們
find that they are not seekers of Truth, they are cheating themselves.
發現他們並非真理的追尋者，他們是在欺騙自己。
A seeker of Truth has his attention all the time inside, on his seeking.
一個真正的求道者始終專注於內裡，專注於他所追尋的真理。
He is not bothered about other things.
他不會為其他事物所困擾。
The seeker wants the Absolute, the Perfect.
求道者渴望的是絕對的，完美的真理。
The seeker doesn’t want something that he’s not seeking.
他不會想要任何不是他在追尋的東西。
That’s why innocence is the best way one can seek.
這就是為什麼純真是最佳的求道方式。
Like a small little child once was lost in a fair.
就像一個小孩曾在市集中走丟了。
So, the child started crying for the mother.
然後，孩子哭著找媽媽，
And the police people got the child in the hand.
警察把他抱了起來。
So, they said, “All right, just now wait, we’ll get your mother, but first of all
警察說：「好了，你先等等，我們馬上去找你媽媽，
you have something else."
不過你先玩玩別的。」
They gave a nice balloon to the child, to play.
他們給了孩子一個漂亮的氣球，讓他玩。
So, the child says, “No, I don’t want any balloon, I don’t want.
然而，孩子卻說：「不，我不要什麼氣球，我不要。
I want my mother."
我要找媽媽。」
So, they said, “All right, let’s take you down, we’ll give you some ice cream
於是他們說：「好吧，我們帶你去，給你一些冰淇淋
to eat, some chocolates."
「吃點巧克力吧。」
The child says, “No, I don’t want any chocolates, I don’t want anything like that.
孩子說：「不，我不要巧克力，我什麼都不要。」
I want the presence of my mother.
我要找到我媽媽。
I want my mother.
我要我媽媽。
I won’t have anything else."
別的我什麼都不要。"
They tried and tried their level best to pacify the child, but the child would not take anything
警察竭盡所能地安撫那個孩子，但孩子什麼都不肯要，
else but would just ask for the mother.
只想要媽媽。
Because child had lost the mother and it was seeking the mother, it was doubting everything
因為孩子失去了母親，要找媽媽，所以對其他一切都感到懷疑
else but that.
唯獨對母親沒有懷疑。
But our sense of discrimination, our sense of understanding, our wisdom is so developed,
但我們的辨別能力、理解力以及智慧如此地發展，
is so foolishly developed, I would say, that we always miss the Truth and grasp the untruth.
或者我該說如此愚蠢地發展，以致我們總是錯過真理，反而抓住謬誤。
I don’t know how human beings can do it?
我不明白人類怎麼能夠做到這樣？
It’s difficult for animals to do but human beings just manage.
動物沒辦法這麼做，人類卻很容易。
That’s all we have done so far in the history, if you see.
若你細看歷史，至今為止我們所做的就是如此。
Such great incarnations came on this Earth.
所有偉大的降世神祇來到這個世界，
What did we do out of their lives?
我們從他們的生命中汲取了什麼？
We crucified them, gave them poisons, we put them in the jails, we did whatever was possible
我們把他們釘上十字架，給他們下毒，將他們關進監獄，我們無所不用其極
out of them.
對付他們
How many followed them, one or two?
有多少人追隨他們？一兩個？
But take Hitler now.
但現在看看希特勒
How many followed him?
有多少人追隨他？
Because we have a special identification with falsehood, not with Truth, we have lived with
因為我們與虛假有著特殊的認同，而非與真理，我們一生都活在
falsehood all our lives.
虛假之中。
Moment to moment you’ll find we are doing like that.
你會發現我們每時每刻都那樣做。
In the name of money, in the name of power, in the war, they say, everything is fair,
以金錢之名，以權力之名，在戰爭中，他們說，一切都是公平的，
in the name of so-called love.
以所謂的愛之名。
With all this, we expect to find the Truth?
憑藉這一切，我們期望找到真理？
Also we expect that Truth should fall at our feet?
我們還期望真理應該俯伏在我們腳下？
So, to all the seekers of the Truth of this world, I request to know that if you are seeking
因此，我要向所有追尋世間真理的尋道者請求：倘若你們確實在探求
the Truth, this time you don’t miss it.
真理，這次別再錯過它。
It is a genuine, absolute, eternal, joy-giving, being within yourself.
這是真實不虛、絕對永恆、能帶來喜悅的本質，它就存在於你之內。
Yourself, within your heart it resides, is the Atma, is the Spirit within you.
在你心中居住的，正是靈（Atma），也就是你內在的靈性本體。
It does not like cheating.
它不喜歡欺騙。
It knows you are cheating, it knows all the field – kshetrAgnya ( the Knower of the
它知道你正在欺騙，它知道一切領域——kshetrAgnya（領域的知曉者）
field).
領域）。
It knows what you are doing, what you are playing with, what you are doubting?
它知道你正在做什麼、在玩弄什麼、在懷疑什麼？
It knows everything.
它知曉一切。
Because this Spirit within you is one with the Whole, it keeps absolutely in harmony,
因為你內在的這個靈與大整體合一，它與整體完全保持和諧，
unison, concord, with the Whole.
一致且協調。
It is we, with our intelligence you may call it, or ego, or superego, whatever it is, we
是我們人類，用你可稱之為智慧、自我或超我，或是任何名詞，我們
try to cheat it.
試圖欺騙它。
It doesn’t like it, at all.
它完全不喜歡這樣。
If you have to become that, if your attention has to get dissolved into that Spirit, then
如果你必須成為真理，如果你的注意力必須融入靈，那麼
keep your attention pure.
你必須保持純淨的注意力。
Purity is the way you are going to get into it.
純淨是你進入其中的途徑。
It is something between you and yourself.
這存在於你與真我之間。
It is something which is your own concern within yourself, it is for you to decide and
這是你內心深處的個人課題，需要由你來決定並
to understand.
理解。
If you are getting vibrations in the hand, if the cool breeze is coming, if your Kundalini
如果你在手上感到生命能量，如果有涼風襲來，如果你的昆達里尼
has touched the Sahasrara, maybe, it is the Grace itself is pouring into you.
已經觸及頂輪，那麼這可能正是恩典本身正傾注於你。
But do not take it for granted.
切勿視為理所當然。
You will not progress fast if you go that slow way.
若以如此緩慢的方式前進，你將難以快速精進。
You can only progress if you go on drenching yourself in that Grace.
唯有持續沉浸在那恩典之中，你才能獲得進步。
This is the first problem of Sahaja Yoga, I find, specially in the West.
這是霎哈嘉瑜珈的第一個問題，我發現在西方尤其明顯。
And that’s why I have seen, that you are more enamoured by people who are not genuine
正因如此，我觀察到你們非常容易被那些不真誠的人所吸引
and least bothered about someone who is absolutely genuine.
而對那些全然真誠的人卻毫不在意。
The second point that comes to My mind, which is very important, the other day I hinted
我腦海中浮現的第二點非常重要，前幾天我略有提及
at it, that when you get your Self-realisation, it’s just the Grace that you get it, at
當你獲得自覺時，那是上天的恩典讓你在
the first shot, you do get it.
第一次嘗試時就真的得到了它
It’s just the Grace that you get it!
這完全是上天的恩典讓你得到了它！
To maintain it, is your job.
維持它，是你的責任。
You lose it very fast, so many of you.
你們之中有許多人，很快就會失去它。
Because as soon as you get it in Sahaja Yoga, you start doubting it.
因為一旦你在霎哈嘉瑜伽中獲得它，你就開始懷疑。
Firstly maybe, because you do not think that you are capable of getting a Self-realisation.
或許首先，是因為你不認為自己有資格獲得自覺。
You undervalue yourself, because you don’t know how much God loves you.
你低估了自己，因為你不知道上帝有多麼愛你。
His creation will be destroyed if He does not give you Self-knowledge.
若祂不賜予你自覺，祂的造物將被毀滅。
It is out of this divine Love that you have got your Self-realisation.
正是出於這份神聖之愛，你才獲得了自覺。
But you lose immediately the vibrations so many of you, because you start doubting.
但你們許多人很快就失去了生命能量，因為你們開始懷疑。
What are you doubting there?
你在懷疑什麼？
Because you are confused!
因為你感到困惑！
What are you going to gain out of doubting or lose out of doubting?
懷疑又能帶給你什麼好處或損失呢？
There is no shop here.
這裡沒有商店。
There is nothing selling.
這裡沒有任何販售行為。
You have paid no money for it.
你沒有為此支付任何金錢。
You are not going to lose your powers or anything.
你不會失去你的權力或任何東西。
If you are a king, you’ll remain a king, may become even a greater king.
如果你是個國王，你將依然是國王，甚至可能成為更偉大的國王。
If you are a student, you might become a better student.
如果你是個學生，你可能會成為一個更優秀的學生。
What is there to lose that you’ve started doubting and playing with it?
你究竟有什麼好失去的，以至於你已經開始懷疑並玩弄它？
Perhaps, very few realise the value of Self-realisation.
或許，很少有人意識到自覺的價值。
I’ve seen the sick realise it more than the healthy people, sometimes, because sick
我見過病人比健康的人更接受自覺，有時候，因為病人
feel comforted in their body.
會因自覺得到身體病痛的舒解
But how shallow we are!
這是多麼膚淺啊！
Just think of it.
想想看吧
Sometimes, this Ambrose, this amrut is given to someone who doesn’t know the value of
有時候，這種聖水，這種甘露會賜給不懂得自覺價值
this.
的人。
I had some great saints in India who told Me, who know Me, and who know My work, that,
在印度，有些偉大的聖者認識我，也了解我的工作，他們告訴我說：
“Mother, You are wasting Your energy on these people, they are no good."
「母親，您在這些人身上浪費精力，他們不值得。」
They don’t want to come down.
他們不願意出來。
I say, “Why do you say like that?
我說：「你為什麼這樣說呢？」
I know they are seekers of the ancient times, they’re great people who have been seeking
我知道他們是從前古代的求道者，他們是偉大的人，一直在追尋
the Truth and today they are born as normal householders."
真理，而今天他們轉世為普通的居家者。」
But they said, “They are so identified with other thing that it is going to be very difficult
但這些聖人說：「他們如此執著其他事物，這將會非常困難
for them to accept the Truth."
讓他們接受真理。」
You have to steady yourself on the platform of Truth, which itself plays around.
你必須在真理的平台上穩住自己，而這個平台本身也在動盪。
It tests you.
它會考驗你。
There are ways of testing you.
有各種方式能考驗你。
Every minute it is testing.
每分每秒都在測試。
You have to settle down on it.
你必須專注於此。
While, I’ve seen many people saying, ” Then why should we lose vibrations?”
然而，我聽過很多人說：「那為什麼我們會失去生命能量？」
I mean, see the attitude, I’m saying.
我的意思是，看看這態度，
You are a seeker.
你是個求道者。
Truth is not the seeker, sir.
真理不是求道者，先生。
You have to settle down there, isn’t it?
你必須在那裡安頓下來，不是嗎？
You have to sit down there, isn’t it?
你必須在那裡坐下，不是嗎？
Because you are going to gain, you are going to get the joy that is Truth, that is Love,
因為你將會獲得，你將會得到那份喜悅，那就是真理，那就是愛，
that is Eternal.
那就是永恆。
It is you are going to benefit.
是你們將會受益。
So, why be that shallow?
所以，為何要如此膚淺呢？
Why be that frivolous?
為何要如此輕浮？
Because you are people, of ancient ages, have been seeking the Truth.
你們是自古以來就一直在尋求真理的人。
There’re people you have seen the other day, I had met a man who was on the TV or
前些日子你見過的那些人中，我曾遇過一位出現在電視上的男子
something and he was talking big thing about wholesomeness and also of seeking and self-knowledge.
他高談闊論著關於健全、追尋與自我認知的大道理。
When he confronted Me, I found him absolutely shallow, good for nothing, absolutely useless
當他面對我時，我覺得他非常膚淺，一無是處，完全沒用
fellow.
的傢伙。
He said,”I must have the experience."
他說：「我必須要有這種體驗。」
I said, “Why must you have, sir?
我問：「你為什麼一定要，先生？
Why do you entitle?
你憑什麼這樣要求？
Because you can give big lecture in BBC, because you have read this book of this man, that
因為你能在 BBC 發表長篇演說，因為你讀過這個人寫的書，那
book of that man?”
個人寫的書？
It judges you, My children, it judges you every minute.
祂在審判你們，我的孩子們，祂每分每秒都在審判你們。
You are judging it, but it judges you!
你們在評判祂，但祂也在審判你們！
Perhaps, I hope in My lifetime, I may be able to see that Truth is dawn upon this Earth,
願在我有生之年，能親眼目睹真理之光普照這片大地，
in your heart and that thousands and thousands of you, who are really the seekers, receive
照亮你們的心靈，讓成千上萬真心尋求真理的人們都能領受
it.
這份恩典。
But it’s a living process.
然而這是一個活生生的進程。
It is not a artificial process.
這不是一個人工的過程。
It is not just a movement, linear movement like that.
這不僅僅像那樣直線性的運動。
It is a living process.
這是一個活生生的過程。
There are so many things that have to work it out.
有如此多關節需要解決。
Like you can have many plastic flowers, but to get one flower, how much time one has to
就像你可以擁有許多塑膠花，但要生成一朵真花，得花多少時間
spend watching it blossoming?
才看的到它綻放？
This growth does not cut anyone, it doesn’t move in a linear way as other growths do:
這個成長不會傷害任何人，它不像其他形式的成長那樣線性發展：
like your power, like your political, economic growths.
像是你的權力、政治或經濟的成長。
They move in lines, they have no relationship with others, you see.
你看，它們成排移動，與其他部分毫無關聯。
There is no relationship with the Whole, they have no sense of proportion.
與整體毫無聯繫，它們毫無比例感。
Like somebody’s nose increasing, somebody’s ears increasing.
就像某人的鼻子變大，某人的耳朵變長。
It’s a cancer!
這是種癌症！
All these movements will lead to cancer, means they will eat you off.
這些運動最終都會變成癌症，意味著它們會逐漸侵蝕你。
They have to eat up somebody to make their way.
它們必須吞噬他人人才能前進。
They just start blindly moving one side, then they cannot turn round.
它們只是盲目地往一邊移動，然後就無法回頭了。
It’s a wholesome, living movement.
真我認知是一個完整、有生命的運動。
And that takes time.
而這需要時間。
It can work out very fast.
它可能會很快見效。
It can go into a chain reaction.
可能引發連鎖反應。
I can assure you: if you all decide to be genuine about it and humble about it, if you
我可以向你們保證：如果你們都決心真誠並謙卑地追求，如果
little bit change your attitude about Sahaja Yoga: that there is nothing selling here,
稍微調整一下你對霎哈嘉瑜伽的看法：這裡並沒有在販售任何東西，
that you are the seeker, you have to knock the door, you have to ask for it and then
你是求道者，必須主動敲門，必須提出請求，
you will be blessed.
然後你才會得到祝福。
This is the biggest gap I find, and that’s why sometimes, I feel extremely helpless.
這是我發現最大問題，也正因如此，有時候我會感到極度無助。
Please, try to understand.
請試著去理解。
Please, understand this is the situation: you are seekers, you are really genuine seekers,
請明白這個情況：你們是求道者，你們是真正真誠的求道者，
you have been seeking for thousands of years.
你們已經尋求了數千年之久。
It has been said in the scriptures.
這在經典中早有記載。
And you are born on this Earth to get your right as the citizen of Kingdom of God.
你降生於此世，是為了獲得作為神國子民的權利。
But seek That!
但要尋求那至高無上的權利！
Do not seek anything else, because nothing else is important, neither fulfilling, nor
不要追求其他任何事物，因為其他一切都無關緊要，既不圓滿，
rewarding, neither perfect.
也沒有意義，更不完美。
Today, we are going to have the meditation now after this.
今天，接下來我們要進行冥想。
In Sahaja Yoga the meditation has only one simple meaning is that the Kundalini has to
在霎哈嘉瑜伽中，冥想只有一個簡單的意義，就是靈量(坤達里尼)必須
rise from the triangular bone there, and has to touch the Sahasrara, here, and open you
從那裡的三角骨升起，並觸碰到這裡的頂輪，開啟你
to the subtle point.
與精微能量的連結。
This is a simple thing, is meditation.
這是一件簡單的事，就是冥想。
After realisation also, meditation means the same that you keep your Kundalini high up
即使在自覺後，冥想表示保持你的昆達里尼高懸。
hanging there.
懸掛在那裡。
You are with the subtle collective consciousness, with the Universal all-pervading power of
你與精微的集體意識同在，與遍及宇宙的無所不在力量同在
God’s love.
神的愛。
Once you are there, you are just hanged up into that blissful state.
一旦你達到那種境界，就會被提升至那極樂的狀態。
Then diseases don’t come to you, then mental tortures don’t come to you.
在那裏疾病無法侵擾你，心靈的折磨也不會找上你。
You become a witness and you become the instrument of that power, which is all-pervading and
你成為見證者，同時也成為那股無所不在力量的工具，
you get the collective consciousness within you.
你內裡取獲得集體意識。
It happens to you.
這會發生在你身上。
If it does not happen to you, then genuinely, there are some defects somewhere, which one
若未發生在你身上，那麼確實存在某些缺陷，
has to correct.
必須改正。
For which I am willing to work hard.
為此我願意努力工作。
And there are so many who have got it also.
而且已經有許多人得到了。
So, you are also going to get it and you are also going to feel it.
所以，你們也將會得到，並且親身感受。
There is no problem about it.
這完全不是問題。
It is a gift, it is not an enticement.
這是上天的恩賜，不是誘惑。
Do not mislead yourself any longer- you have done quite a lot.
不要再誤導自己了——你已經做夠了。
Now please, receive the gift and establish it within yourself.
現在請這份恩賜，並讓它在你的內裡深處紮根。
Do not identify yourself with all false ideas.
不要把自己認同於所有錯誤的觀念。
Say, if you are a Christian then, ‘I am a Christian.
比方說，如果你是基督徒，那麼就說「我是基督徒。
Only Christ is the One.’
唯獨基督才是真理。」
Yes, He is the One, no doubt, but He means many thing.
是的，毫無疑問祂是真理，但祂的意義遠不止於此。或者
Or if I’m a Muslim, then Mohammed Sahib is the only One.
又如果我是一位回教徒，那麼穆罕默德就是唯一的真主。
Or if I’m a Jew, then I do not believe in Christ.
又如果我是一位猶太教徒，那麼我就不相信基督。
There are many like these mad caps all around.
到處都有許多像這樣瘋狂的傢伙。
You are not that type!
不要成為那種人！
Get over these boundaries and false identifications and raise your vision higher, which is called
跨越這些界線與錯誤的認知，將你的視野提升至更高境界，這就是所謂的
as adhishthana, you put yourself higher than what you are.
超越（adhishthana），把自己置於比現狀更高的位置。
Which you are!
這正是你的本質！
And just say that, “I’m a seeker of Truth!
只需宣告：「我是真理的追尋者！」
Does this behove me, my personality.
這樣的想法與我的人格相符嗎？
How can I think like that about it!”
我怎麼能那樣想呢！
The Truth has to be universal and has to be for all of them, whether they are Christians,
真理必須是普世的，必須適用於所有人，無論他們是基督徒、
Jews, Hindus, Muslims, atheist.
猶太徒、印度教徒、回教徒、佛教道教還是無神論者。
It has to be for every one of you.
這必須適用於你們每一個人。
So, you do not put it into compartments and strangle it, because then that is the end
所以，你不能將它分門別類並扼殺它，因為那意味著
for your seeking.
扼殺你探尋的終點。
That is the death of your seeking.
那將是求道的死亡。
As I told you before, a tree has many flowers and it has beautiful, one, whole personality.
正如我之前告訴你的，一棵樹有許多花朵，它有著美麗且完整的人格。
People take the flowers with them saying, “This is my flower.
人們摘走花朵時會說：「這是我的花。」
This is my flower."
「這是我的花。」
They remove it from the whole and the flowers become ugly and die out.
他們將花從整體中分離，這些花朵因此變得醜陋並逐漸凋萎。
The sap of life moves in the tree all over, it does not stick on to one flower because
生命的汁液在整棵樹中流動，它不會因為一朵花而停留，
it is one in unison with the power of God.
因為它與神的力量合而為一。
We, human beings, are separated, specially for the purpose of our independent development,
我們人類被分離開來，是為了讓我們能獨立發展，
but, in our wisdom we should be able to see all this around us and learn from it.
但以我們的智慧，應該看的到周遭的一切並從中學習。
There are so many thing which teach us that do not get into compartments.
有許多事物教導我們不要把自己局限在框架中。
Does a tree say that ‘I belong to England’ or ‘I belong to India’?
一棵樹會說「我屬於英國」或「我屬於印度」嗎？
If it cannot prosper in one climate, it does not, that’s all.
如果它無法在某種氣候下茁壯成長，那就不會成長，僅此而已。
As human beings you are the highest and are the wisest and the best.
作為人類，你們是最崇高、最明智且最優秀的。
Let God see how this blossoming time flowers you into beautiful fruits of His work, of
讓上帝看看這開花期你將如何地綻放、成為祂事工的美麗果實，
His creation.
祂的創造。
May God bless you all!
願上帝保佑你們所有人！
Will you put your hands like this, towards Me, just like this and take out your shoes?
請你們像這樣把手伸向我，就這樣，然後把鞋子脫掉好嗎？
Now, you are here for seeking and not for any mental acrobatics.
此刻，你們來此是為尋求，而非任何頭腦雜技。
So, please, tell your mind to shut up for a while.
所以，拜託，請叫你的腦袋安靜一下。
So far you have not been able to find it.
到目前為止你還沒能找到真理。
All right, so let us go ahead.
好的，讓我們開始吧。
And now do not put your mind to any exercise.
不要讓你的腦子去做任何練習。
Just put your hands in a very simple manner like this, in a most comfortable position.
就這麼簡單地把手放著，以最舒適的姿勢。
Do not put any strain on your body.
不要讓身體有任何緊繃。
If there is anything tight, please, remove it.
如果有任何束縛，請務必解開。
And let us sit little comfortably.
讓我們坐得舒服些吧。
Just most comfortably, but put both the feet touching on the ground.
就最舒適地，但雙腳要接觸地面。
[Pause for 2 minutes]
[停頓 2 分鐘]
Please, close your eyes.
請閉上眼睛。
Please, close your eyes, because when Kundalini crosses over the Agnya, there’s a dilatation
請閉上眼睛，因為當坤達里尼通過額輪時，瞳孔
of the pupil.
會擴張。
And then eyes little bit, you see a little bit, blind for a little while, but please,
然後眼睛稍微閉一下，你會看到一點點，暫時看不見一會兒，但是請，
keep them closed, otherwise the Kundalini won’t cross, you see, because She doesn’t
眼睛保持閉著，否則昆達里尼無法通過，你知道嗎，因為祂不想
want to disturb you, you see.
打擾到你，你明白嗎。
So, She’ll keep below the Agnya.
她會留在額輪之下。
Now, if you cannot close your eyes properly, in the sense that there is a little flickering
現在，如果你無法完全閉上眼睛，意思是眼皮有些顫動，
in the eyelids, please, open them.
請睜開眼睛。
[Pause for 30 seconds]
[停頓 30 秒]
Don’t be angry with yourself, you see.
別對自己生氣，你看。
It is not true of everyone what I said you.
我對你說的話並不是每個人都適用。
But it is a little bit in everyone of us, a little bit of that lacking sometimes, you
但在我們每個人身上都有一點點，有時會稍微缺乏這點，你
see.
知道嗎。
So, please, don’t be angry with yourself, but love yourself.
所以，請別對自己生氣，而是要愛自己。
By loving you will be able to judge it; what is good and bad for you.
透過愛，你將能夠判斷什麼對你是有益或有害的。
Just don’t think about it.
只要別去想它。
It will work without thinking.
它會在你不思考的時候自然運作。
With thinking it is not going to work out.
光用想的行不通。
So, just leave your thinking one side.
所以，先把你的思緒放一邊。
You’ve not to think.
你必須停止思考。
Most of you have become blank.
你們大多數人已經放空了。
[Pause for 30 seconds]
停頓 30 秒]
You have to get it like a small child wants to have his mother.
你必須像一個小孩渴望母親那樣地去追求。
In the same way, you have to get to the Truth.
同樣地，你必須如此追求真理。
That’s all, very simple.
就是這樣，非常簡單。
But tell your mind to rest a while, not to take you to too much thinking.
告訴你的腦袋稍微休息一下，別讓你陷入過多思考。
That is very important, because this mind only cheats you all the time.
這非常重要，因為這個腦袋會欺騙你。
Train it up properly.
好好訓練它。
[ASIDE] You should record it, vibrations.
[旁白] 你該錄下來，那些生命能量。
[Pause for 2 minutes]
[停頓 2 分鐘]
If you are getting any cool breeze in your hand…
如果你手上感覺到任何涼風…
All those who have come for the first time should see if there is any cool breeze coming
所有初次到來的人都應該看看是否有涼風
in your hand, through your fingers, fingertips.
從你的手指或指尖流過。
[Pause for 30 seconds]
[停頓 30 秒]
You are [UNCLEAR] to the experience.
你對這個體驗[不清楚]。
Very good.
非常好。
[Pause for one and half minutes]
[停頓一分半鐘]
Now, those who are getting cool breeze, please, raise your hands, all of you.
那些感受到涼風的人，請舉起你們的手，所有感受到的人都舉手。
Mother addressing somebody in Hindi.
母親用印地語對某人說話。
Tumhe nahi aa rahe?
你沒有感覺到嗎？
(Means ‘You are not getting?’)
（意思是『你沒感覺到嗎？』）
[rest is UNCLEAR]
[其餘部分不清楚]
Those who have come today for the first time, please, raise your hands who are getting cool
今天第一次來的人，請舉手，如果有感受到涼風
breeze.
涼風的話。
For the first time…
第一次...
Mother asking a Sahaja yogi: “Aa raha hai unke cool breeze?
母親問一個霎哈嘉瑜伽修行者：「他們感受到涼風了嗎？」
Nahi aa raha?
沒有嗎？
Unko bandhan do tou tumhara aa jayega."
如果給他們"般單"，你就會感受到。
[Meaning: “Is he getting cool breeze?
[意思：他是否感受到涼風？
Not getting?
沒有感受到嗎？
If you give bandhan to him then you will get it."
如果你給他上般單(bandhan)，那麼你就會
]
感受到。"
Now, those who have come for the first time and are not getting cool breeze, please, raise
初次前來卻未感受到涼風的人，請舉起
your hands.
你們的手。
First time and are not getting cool breeze, please, raise your hands.
初次來此卻未感受到涼風的人，請舉起你們的手。
Have you come for the first time?
你是第一次來嗎？
Have you?
有人舉手了嗎？
This lady… ask her.
這位女士...問問她。
Have you come…
你感覺到涼風吹到手上了嗎？
Yes.
是的。
Are you getting cool breeze in the hand?
你手上有感受到涼風嗎？
Then raise your hands.
那就舉起你的手。
Did you follow My point?
你明白我的意思嗎？
Those who have come for the first time and are not getting cool breeze, please, raise
第一次來卻沒有感受到涼風的，請舉起
your hands.
你們的手。
Hanna is he getting cool breeze?
漢娜，他有感受到涼風嗎？
Haan?
嗯？
[Meaning: ‘Yes?’]
[意思是：『怎麼了？』]
What’s the matter?
有什麼事嗎？
Doubting?
在懷疑嗎？
You are going to waste all your time, like this, My child…
你這樣會浪費時間，我的孩子...
[Unclear] How are you going to listen?
[不清楚] 你要怎麼聽？
Please, raise…
請，手舉起來...
Are you getting cool breeze?
你有感覺到涼風嗎？
No.
沒有。
Then again, raise again…
再來一次，再舉一次手…
All of you who have come for the first time and are not getting cool breeze, please, raise
所有第一次來這裡卻沒有感受到涼風的人，請舉起
your hands.
你們的手。
Are you getting cool breeze?
你們有感受到涼風嗎？
Good.
好。
[Unclear] I’m so happy!
[聽不清楚] 我太高興了！
Very happy!
非常高興！
You all have got.
你們都感受到了。
Are you feeling better now?
你現在感覺好點了嗎？
One, two, three, four…and four…
一、二、三、四...還有四...
What about that lady there?
那邊那位女士怎麼樣？
Are you getting cool breeze, no?
你有感覺到涼風嗎，沒有嗎？
Getting it?
有嗎？
Very good!
非常好！
All right, let it work out.
沒問題，讓它自然發展。
Close your eyes, it will work out, all right?
閉上眼睛，會順利解決的，好嗎？
Only four people are not getting vibrations.
只有四個人沒有感受到生命能量。
Have you been to any gurus?
你有去見過任何靈性導師嗎？
Guru, guru.
古魯，古魯。
What you call them, masters or gurus or I don’t know… what all names.
你怎麼稱呼他們，大師或古魯，我不知道...還有什麼名稱
What do you say to gurus?
靈性導師?